Guide to the Records of Graham Windham 1804-2011 MS 2916
New-York Historical Society
- Series III - Graham Windham, 1970-2011 (bulk 1977-2010)
  - Subseries III.9 - Office of Development - Photographic Materials, circa 1978-2010
    - Annual Meeting, 1992 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 12)
    - Michael Ainslie and Joyce Lapenn on Campus School, 1992 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 13)
    - Bruce Fowle, Board Member, 1992 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 14)
    - Marian Taylor, Board Member, 1992 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 15)
    - Photos of Donors, Chase, Food Co-Op, 1992 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 16)
    - Michael Golden, Board Member, undated (Offsite-box 101, Folder 17)
    - Horace Hord, Board Member, undated (Offsite-box 101, Folder 18)
    - Barbara Willis Hearst, undated (Offsite-box 101, Folder 19)
    - Diane D. Schlinkert, Board Member, undated (Offsite-box 101, Folder 20)
    - Charlotte Ottley, Board Member, undated (Offsite-box 101, Folder 21)
    - Suzanne Bales, Board Member, undated (Offsite-box 101, Folder 22)
    - Solomon House, circa 1983-1985 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 1)
    - Negatives - Unidentified Sites - Holiday Times, undated and 1985 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 2)
    - 1980s? Art Show, undated (Offsite-box 102, Folder 3)
    - Crafts Workshop - Brooklyn Junior League for Family Day Care in Brooklyn, 1996 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 4)
    - Campus Harvest Time, circa 1994 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 5)
    - Davidson Avenue Dedication, 1998 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 6)
    - Holiday Staff Party, 2003 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 7)
    - Bronxville Friends Holiday in Harlem Center, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous including Basketball Clinic, circa 1990-2010 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 9)
    - Holiday Party, undated (Offsite-box 102, Folder 10)
    - GW Young Professionals at Beacon Center, undated (Offsite-box 102, Folder 11)
    - Halloween at ?, undated (Offsite-box 102, Folder 12)
    - Countee Cullen Literary Academy ??, undated (Offsite-box 102, Folder 13)
    - Campus?, 1999 and undated (Offsite-box 102, Folder 14)
    - Children's Art Classes, undated (Offsite-box 102, Folder 15)
    - Drawing of Mother and Child?, undated (Offsite-box 102, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Various Sites, undated (Offsite-box 103, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs to be Identified, undated (Offsite-box 103, Folder 2)
    - Visit to Puerto Rico - 2 Photograph Albums, 1992 (Offsite-box 104)
    - Visit to Puerto Rico 1992 (1 Photograph Album) and Staff Party 1994 (3 Photograph Albums), 1992-1994 (Offsite-box 105)
    - Photograph Album: [Staff Party 1994] and Photograph Album: Staff Party 2001, circa 1994-2001 (Offsite-box 106)
    - Photograph Binder, 1994 (Offsite-box 145, Volume 219)
    - Photograph Binder, 1994-1995 (Offsite-box 145, Volume 220)
    - Photograph Binder, 1995 (Offsite-box 146, Volume 221)
    - Photograph Binder, 1995-1997 (Offsite-box 146, Volume 222)
  - Subseries III.10 - Artifacts, 1986-2002
    The subseries consists of a mounted letter from Ronald Reagan, 1 proclamation (formerly framed, now removed from its frame for conservation purposes), 1 accreditation notice mounted as a plaque, and 1 award plaque.
    - Mounted Letter from Ronald Reagan, 1986 March 13 (Box OS 1, Folder 5)
    - Resolucion del Alcalde, Ciudad de Ponce, Ponce Puerto Rico, 1992 April 16 (Box OS 1, Folder 5)
    - Middle States Accreditation, mounted on wood, 1992 April 15 (Offsite-box OS 3)
    - Children's Champion Award Plaque, 2002 (Offsite-box OS 3)
- Series IV - The Society for the Relief of Poor Widows with Children circa 1804-1881; the New York Methodist Sunday School Society 1835-1837; and the Tuberculosis Preventorium for Children 1910-1949, circa 1804-1949
  The series consists of three pages of original minutes from a February 11 1804 meeting of a subcommittee of the Society for the Relief of Poor Widows with Small Children (SRPW), with an additional document from April 1881 glued to it. The SRPW was Isabella Graham's earlier organization, out of which the Orphan Asylum Society (OAS) was founded in 1806 as a separate organization. The 1804 document refers to the decision of some SRPW volunteers to educate the children of the poor widows. The document was later framed in cardboard by an unknown person at the OAS, who presumably also wrote and attached the 1881 document as an introduction to the 1804 document. The deteriorating cardboard was removed at the New-York Historical Society in order to conserve the document. The New-York Historical Society also has among its collections eight volumes of board minutes (1797-1932) from the SRPW. The 3-page document in this series is not duplicated in the SRPW board minutes volumes.
  The series also contains one volume of minutes of The New York Methodist Sunday School Society of the West Circuit from May 28, 1835 (the date of its founding) to October 25, 1837. The second half of the handwritten volume is a ledger recording receipts and cash expenses for a household, farm, and garden, created by an unknown person 1844-1851, and a detailed record of varieties of tulips and other flowers planted 1854-1855. It appears that the minutes book was repurposed as a ledger. The relationship of the creator of the first half of the volume to the creator of the second half of the volume is unknown. The reason this volume is in the Graham Windham collection is also unknown.
  The series also contains one small box containing reports and correspondence from the Tuberculosis Preventorium for Children 1910-1921, and an annual report from that organization from 1949. The annual report also provides a summary of the organization from its founding in 1909 through 1948. The Tuberculosis Preventorium, located in Farmingdale New Jersey, merged into Windham Child Care in 1949.
  These three group of records are arranged in chronological order.
  New York Methodist Sunday School Society
  - Society for the Relief of Poor Widows with Small Children Minutes and Additional Document, 1804 February 11 and 1881 April (Offsite-box 107, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the New York Methodist Sunday School Society of the West Circuit and Ledger by Unknown Creator, 1835-1855 (Offsite-box 135, Volume 223)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Correspondence and Reports, 1910-1914 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 2)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Correspondence, 1914-1915 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 3)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Correspondence, 1915-1916 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 4)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Correspondence and Reports, 1917-1921 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 5)
  - Tuberculosis Preventorium Annual Report, 1949 (Offsite-box 107, Folder 6)